Finding Aid for St. Luke's Episcopal Church (Ypsilanti, Mich.) records, 1836-ca. 2000
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
St. Luke's Episcopal Church (Ypsilanti, Mich.) records 1836-circa 2000
St. Luke's Episcopal Church (Ypsilanti, Mich.)
4 oversize volumes
9 linear feet
86940 Ba 2; BA Outsize
Records of vestry and congregational meetings; parish registers, records of women's guild and women's auxiliary; and treasurer's record book.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records were acquired in several accessions, beginning in December 1958 (donor no. 3484 ).
Periodic additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
St. Luke's Church was founded in 1830 (its first name was St. James') as a result of missionary work to the area undertaken by the Rev. Richard Fish Cadle and the Green Bay Indian Mission. Later in 1834, following the loss of several families, the church was reorganized. In 1836, a preaching mission to the Ypsilanti area was established, and in 1838, the first church building was consecrated.
The records of St. Luke's include minutes of vestry and congregational meetings; registers of members, baptisms, marriages, etc.; registers of church services; church publications; scrapbooks detailing activities; photographs; and record books for church women's organizations.
Subjects:
Episcopal Church--Michigan--Ypsilanti.; St. Luke's Episcopal Church (Ypsilanti, Mich.); Women--Michigan--Ypsilanti--Societies and clubs.; Ypsilanti (Mich.); Women--Religious life--Michigan--Ypsilanti.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
St. Luke's Episcopal Church (Ypsilanti, Mich.); Churches--Michigan--Ypsilanti.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Record books 1837-1988
  (minutes of vestry and congregational meetings)
  - 1837-1864 (Box 1)
  - 1864-1926 (Box 1)
  - 1927-1947 (Box 1)
  - 1947-1958 (Box 1)
  - 1959-1972 (Box 1)
  - 1972-1982 (Box 1)
  - 1982-1988 (Box 1)
- Registers of members, baptisms, marriages, etc. 1936-1990
  - H.P. Powers memorandum book 1836-1847 including church history, records of baptisms, marriages, and funerals 1839-1893 (Box 2)
  - 1882-1900 (Box 2)
  - 1897-1915 (Box 2)
  - 1915-1942 (Volume 1)
  - 1943-1953 (Volume 2)
  - 1915-1977 (marriages only) (Volume 3)
  - 1977-1990 (marriages only) (Box 2)
- Register of Church Services 1915-1994
  - 1915-1926 (Box 3)
  - 1926-1934 (Box 3)
  - 1953-1962 (Box 3)
  - 1962-1970 (Box 3)
  - 1970-1980 (Box 3)
  - 1980-1984 (Box 3)
  - 1984-1994 (Box 3)
- Miscellaneous records 1906-1992
  - Miscellaneous annual reports and financial reports 1946-1956 (scattered dates) (Box 4)
  - Notebooks containing vestry minutes, financial reports, and annual parish meeting reports 1958-1992 (missing 1983) (Box 4)
  - Treasurer's record book 1906-1913 (Volume 4)
- Publications
  - Newsletters 1959-1998 (Box 5)
    - 1959-1992, 6 folders (Box 5)
    - 1993-1998, 6 folders (Box 6)
  - Church Worship Bulletins 1982-1998
    (missing 1987)
    - 1982-1994, 7 folders (Box 6)
    - 1995-1998, 4 folders (Box 7)
  - St. Luke's Cloister Garth (Box 7)
  - Title Abstract 1915 (Box 7)
  - Church directories and related historical material (Box 7)
- Scrapbooks 1960-1999
  - 1960-1979 (Box 8)
  - 1980-1989 (Box 8)
  - 1990-1999 (Box 8)
- Photographs
  - Photograph albums of church activities, 1940s- circa 2000, 3 volumes (Box 8)
  - Photo of church banquet (Box 8)
  - Slides of stained glass windows, and of church activities and programs (Box 8)
- Women's church groups 1863-1932
  - Ladies Church Aid Society proceedings 1863-1869 (Box 9)
  - Parish Aid and Women's Auxiliary
    - Record books 1891-1905 (Box 9)
      - Record book 1891-1893 (Box 9)
      - Record book 1893-1896 (Box 9)
      - Day book 1895-1903 (Box 9)
      - Record book 1903-1905 (Box 9)
  - Women's Guild record books
    - 1917-1924 (Box 9)
    - 1924-1929 (Box 9)
    - 1933-1934 of Auxiliary Guild (Box 9)
  - Women's Auxiliary record books
    - 1919-1924 (Box 9)
    - 1924-1932 (Box 9)
    - 1932 (Box 9)